<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Python | Dr. Franco Donati</title>
    <link>//localhost:1313/tags/python/</link>
      <atom:link href="//localhost:1313/tags/python/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Python</description>
    <generator>Hugo Blox Builder (https://hugoblox.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 16 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>//localhost:1313/media/icon_hu5178c02e4dac319ecd6d0bb73a2fd450_36029_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Python</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/tags/python/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Advanced course on Environmental Input-Output Analysis</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/teaching/eeioa/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/teaching/eeioa/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;course-description&#34;&gt;Course description&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this course, students systematically study Environmentally-extended Input-Output Analysis (EEIOA). EEIOA is a standard methodology for assessing environmental footprints (e.g. carbon footprints) and analyzing the production and consumption structures within one or across economies. Economic and environmental analyses are inherently integrated for EEIOA.
The course is divided into two parts. The first part introduces the fundamental concepts and quantifications of EEIOA, such as the monetary and physical input-output tables and environmental footprint calculations for nations. The second part of the course introduces several advanced EEIOA techniques and illustrates how they have been used for analyzing sustainability issues, such as the socio-economic and environmental effects of international trade and circular economy strategies, the main immediate drivers of changing environmental pressures imposed by human activities (e.g. CO2 emissions), and sustainable waste management from producers, consumers, and systems perspectives.
The course follows a hands-on approach. Each new lecture is accompanied by an individual assignment, in which students do exercises related to the new content and develop and apply python programming skills. As a 10-EC course, the weekly study load is about 10 hours.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;course-objectives&#34;&gt;Course objectives&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After completing this course, students are expected to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Understand the structures and key components of supply-use tables (SUTs), input-output (IO) tables, and main IO datasets.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Model, in Python, and analyze the economic and environmental effects of production and consumption activities and potential policies across supply chains.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Articulate the state-of-the-art EEIOA methods introduced in the course and their applications in sustainability research and real-world decision-making.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Develop and present a quantitative study using EEIOA, interpreting its main results and potential limitations.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;more-info&#34;&gt;More info&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://studiegids.universiteitleiden.nl/en/courses/123918/environmental-input-output-analysis&#34;&gt;Click here for more information&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Other projects</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/project/other_projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/project/other_projects/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Here is a list of additional project I have worked on through the years&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pycirk</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/project/pycirk/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/project/pycirk/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A python3 package to create and analyze Circular Economy scenarios.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;what-is-pycirk&#34;&gt;What is pycirk&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pycirck is a python package to model Circular Economy policy and technological interventions in multi-regional Environmentally Extended Input-Output Analysis (mrEEIO). The software allows to define an indefinite number of changes in all matrices of the mrEEIO system and an indefinite number of scenario. Furthermore, it allows to easily set multiple parameters for results so that users can investigate different dimensions of the economic system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;how-to-use-pycirk&#34;&gt;How to use Pycirk&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can install the stable version for python 3 through pip install pycirk  &lt;a href=&#34;https://pypi.org/project/pycirk/&#34;&gt;https://pypi.org/project/pycirk/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Or you can install development version as well as contribute to the project by visiting &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/CMLPlatform/pycirk&#34;&gt;https://github.com/CMLPlatform/pycirk&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;master-students&#34;&gt;Master students&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have plenty of opportunities for field work and computer science applications in Industrial Ecology.
If you are interested in doing an internship or conducting your MSc thesis in this area feel free to reach out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;mailto:f.donati@cml.leidenuniv.nl?subject=Circular%20Economy:%20MSc%20thesis/internship&#34;&gt;Send me a message &amp;#x270b;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;collaborations&#34;&gt;Collaborations&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am always happy to discuss new opportunities, please feel free to reach out to discuss potential collaborations&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;mailto:f.donati@cml.leidenuniv.nl?subject=Circular%20Economy:%20Collaborations&#34;&gt;Send me a message &amp;#x270b;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RaMa-Scene</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/project/ramascene/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/project/ramascene/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A web-application to assess the socio-economic and environmental implications of Circular Economy scenarios at the macro-economic level&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
