<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Teaching | Dr. Franco Donati</title>
    <link>//localhost:1313/teaching/</link>
      <atom:link href="//localhost:1313/teaching/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Teaching</description>
    <generator>Hugo Blox Builder (https://hugoblox.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 16 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>//localhost:1313/media/icon_hu5178c02e4dac319ecd6d0bb73a2fd450_36029_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Teaching</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/teaching/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Advanced course on Environmental Input-Output Analysis</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/teaching/eeioa/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/teaching/eeioa/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;course-description&#34;&gt;Course description&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this course, students systematically study Environmentally-extended Input-Output Analysis (EEIOA). EEIOA is a standard methodology for assessing environmental footprints (e.g. carbon footprints) and analyzing the production and consumption structures within one or across economies. Economic and environmental analyses are inherently integrated for EEIOA.
The course is divided into two parts. The first part introduces the fundamental concepts and quantifications of EEIOA, such as the monetary and physical input-output tables and environmental footprint calculations for nations. The second part of the course introduces several advanced EEIOA techniques and illustrates how they have been used for analyzing sustainability issues, such as the socio-economic and environmental effects of international trade and circular economy strategies, the main immediate drivers of changing environmental pressures imposed by human activities (e.g. CO2 emissions), and sustainable waste management from producers, consumers, and systems perspectives.
The course follows a hands-on approach. Each new lecture is accompanied by an individual assignment, in which students do exercises related to the new content and develop and apply python programming skills. As a 10-EC course, the weekly study load is about 10 hours.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;course-objectives&#34;&gt;Course objectives&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After completing this course, students are expected to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Understand the structures and key components of supply-use tables (SUTs), input-output (IO) tables, and main IO datasets.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Model, in Python, and analyze the economic and environmental effects of production and consumption activities and potential policies across supply chains.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Articulate the state-of-the-art EEIOA methods introduced in the course and their applications in sustainability research and real-world decision-making.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Develop and present a quantitative study using EEIOA, interpreting its main results and potential limitations.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;more-info&#34;&gt;More info&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://studiegids.universiteitleiden.nl/en/courses/123918/environmental-input-output-analysis&#34;&gt;Click here for more information&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MSc theses</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/teaching/msc_thesis/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/teaching/msc_thesis/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;potential-future-topics&#34;&gt;Potential future topics&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Artificial Intelligence related topics:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reverse engineering and investigative approaches for LCA&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How to go from product disassembly to LCA&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Artificial Intelligence and digital technology applications in industrial ecology&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;FAIR and Data Quality Assessment in industrial ecology&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Environmental Impacts of AI and Digital Twins&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Collaborative approaches for AI (e.g., citizen science) in industrial ecology&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Circular economy related topics:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Information Systems for the circular economy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Modelling circular economy scenarios for products and business models, and Design for X practices at the macro-economic level or at the border between Micro-Meso-Macro levels&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hydrogen scenarios for steel manufacturing using EEIOA&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rebound effects of CE using EEIOA&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Software tool development for CE assessment&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;mailto:f.donati@cml.leidenuniv.nl?subject=MSc%20thesis/internship%20topic%20interest&#34;&gt;Send me a message if any of these topics speak to you &amp;#x270b;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;current-and-past-theses&#34;&gt;Current and past theses&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As 1st supervisor:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PeDALI: A Pedigree matrix approach for data-driven Data quality Assessment for Life cycle Inventories (Floor Bagchus)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Circular Economy Strategies for Metals: Assessing the Impact of Circularity Interventions on the Dutch Economy by 2050 (Reginold Jesuratnam)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The environmental impacts of current and future biofuel consumption by the Dutch maritime sector. (Kevin Heideman)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As 2nd/3rd supervisor&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From Sewage to Coal: New insights in Char Production: Performance evaluation with a combined Process Simulation and ex-ante Life Cycle Assessment (Heiko Rossdeutscher)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Machine learning in ex-ante LCA: assessing enhancements of forecasting algorithms through systematic literature review and case studies (Nils Pauliks)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thesis Preparation Course</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/teaching/tpc/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/teaching/tpc/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;course-description&#34;&gt;Course description&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During the course, students follow a guided approach towards writing a thesis proposal. Through their identified topics, students define the research gap and research questions concerning their research, and learn how to motivate the work and explain how methods help in achieving the research objective. Students become more competent in the design and planning of research projects by learning how to design research flow diagrams, Gantt charts, and breakdown the work in smaller manageable tasks with clear objectives. Students also learn how to provide insightful peer-review to fellow researchers, and as a result become more critical of their own work and writing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The final outcome of the participation in this course is a research proposal that serves as a tool to guide the student through their Thesis Research Project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;course-objectives&#34;&gt;Course objectives&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After completing this course, students will be able to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Write a scientific research proposal&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Elaborate problem statements and motivate their research&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Perform a literature review to identify core concepts and a research gap&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Formulate effective and clear research questions, hypotheses, aims and objectives&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Articulate methods and data requirements coherent with the research questions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Draw research diagrams and Gantt charts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Create a time-bound research plan&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Provide peer-reviews&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;more-info&#34;&gt;More info&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://studiegids.universiteitleiden.nl/en/courses/123912/thesis-preparation-course-msc-ie-first-semester&#34;&gt;Click here for more information&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
