<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects | Dr. Franco Donati</title>
    <link>//localhost:1313/project/</link>
      <atom:link href="//localhost:1313/project/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Projects</description>
    <generator>Hugo Blox Builder (https://hugoblox.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 16 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>//localhost:1313/media/icon_hu5178c02e4dac319ecd6d0bb73a2fd450_36029_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/project/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reverse engineering labs</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/project/rel/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/project/rel/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Development of a citizen science and digital-twin infrastructure to reverse engineer products and obtain their Life Cycle Inventories.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-problem&#34;&gt;The problem&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most durable goods currently on the market never undergo environmental assessment. This is partially due to challenging and slow process of data collection for Life Cycle Assessment, requiring the involvement of various stakeholders.To further promote sustainability, recent policy developments now require the use of digital product passports and green deal dataspaces where information on the products’ life cycle will be stored. However, we currently miss information systems that can effectively support compliance to these requirements, all the while promoting products’ environmental impacts monitoring and optimization.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-objective&#34;&gt;The objective&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To rapidly expand environmental information on existing durable goods through the development of an infrastructure, data collection systems and protocols to allow practitioners and interested citizens to reverse engineer products and obtain their Life Cycle Inventories and envirommental impacts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;master-students&#34;&gt;Master students&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have plenty of opportunities for field work and computer science applications in Industrial Ecology.
If you are interested in doing an internship or conducting your MSc thesis in this area feel free to reach out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;mailto:f.donati@cml.leidenuniv.nl?subject=Reverse%20engineering%20labs:%20MSc%20thesis/internship&#34;&gt;Send me a message &amp;#x270b;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;collaborations&#34;&gt;Collaborations&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are currently collaborating with academic and industrial partners to get this project running.
But I am always happy to discuss new opportunities, please feel free to reach out to discuss potential collaborations&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;mailto:f.donati@cml.leidenuniv.nl?subject=Reverse%20engineering%20labs:%20Collaborations&#34;&gt;Send me a message &amp;#x270b;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>H2STEEL</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/project/h2steel/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/project/h2steel/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;H2STEEL: Green H2 and circular bio-coal from biowaste for cost-competitive sustainable Steel&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Other projects</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/project/other_projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/project/other_projects/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Here is a list of additional project I have worked on through the years&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pycirk</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/project/pycirk/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/project/pycirk/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A python3 package to create and analyze Circular Economy scenarios.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;what-is-pycirk&#34;&gt;What is pycirk&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pycirck is a python package to model Circular Economy policy and technological interventions in multi-regional Environmentally Extended Input-Output Analysis (mrEEIO). The software allows to define an indefinite number of changes in all matrices of the mrEEIO system and an indefinite number of scenario. Furthermore, it allows to easily set multiple parameters for results so that users can investigate different dimensions of the economic system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;how-to-use-pycirk&#34;&gt;How to use Pycirk&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can install the stable version for python 3 through pip install pycirk  &lt;a href=&#34;https://pypi.org/project/pycirk/&#34;&gt;https://pypi.org/project/pycirk/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Or you can install development version as well as contribute to the project by visiting &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/CMLPlatform/pycirk&#34;&gt;https://github.com/CMLPlatform/pycirk&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;master-students&#34;&gt;Master students&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have plenty of opportunities for field work and computer science applications in Industrial Ecology.
If you are interested in doing an internship or conducting your MSc thesis in this area feel free to reach out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;mailto:f.donati@cml.leidenuniv.nl?subject=Circular%20Economy:%20MSc%20thesis/internship&#34;&gt;Send me a message &amp;#x270b;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;collaborations&#34;&gt;Collaborations&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am always happy to discuss new opportunities, please feel free to reach out to discuss potential collaborations&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;mailto:f.donati@cml.leidenuniv.nl?subject=Circular%20Economy:%20Collaborations&#34;&gt;Send me a message &amp;#x270b;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RaMa-Scene</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/project/ramascene/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/project/ramascene/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A web-application to assess the socio-economic and environmental implications of Circular Economy scenarios at the macro-economic level&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
